<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Bernies Blog - How Things Work</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/how-things-work.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2022-08-02T20:34:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Fixing Gnarly Spark Queries Part 1</title><link href="/fixing-gnarly-spark-queries-part-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-08-02T20:34:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-08-02T20:34:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Bernie</name></author><id>tag:None,2022-08-02:/fixing-gnarly-spark-queries-part-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Fixing Gnarly Spark Queries Part 1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of reflecting on work I've done, I wanted to start by sharing how I approach Spark Optimizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a love-hate relationship with Spark. You can process incredible amounts of data with it. You can also find yourself looking at hanging tasks …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Fixing Gnarly Spark Queries Part 1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of reflecting on work I've done, I wanted to start by sharing how I approach Spark Optimizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a love-hate relationship with Spark. You can process incredible amounts of data with it. You can also find yourself looking at hanging tasks, crazy compute costs, and silly storage situations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When someone called me in to help with a workload in Spark, I tried to really hone in on the following before starting any hands on coding work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What's the objective?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What's the current baseline performance?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do we know that any changes we introduce will still produce appropriate output? IE Do we know what correct-enough looks like?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The majority of the situations I was brought in to help with were focused on meeting some kind of time based deadline IE we need to speed this workload up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Symptoms I looked at:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What jobs are taking the longest?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Within those jobs, do the stages make sense? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Within a stage, how well distributed are the tasks?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I solved the vast majority of issues just within the Spark UI. It's pretty great and I could do a whole post about it if there's interest!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of this needs to be in the context of that objective you set up front with the work plan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good portion of the workloads I've encountered can be addressed by taking a look at how often shuffles are occurring and how often executors are staying idle. 
If you are interested in a deep dive into any of these topics let me know!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="How Things Work"></category></entry></feed>